{"Question 1":{"Choice_0":"Major nutrient deficiencies","Choice_1":"Micronutrient deficiencies","Choice_2":"Nitrogen deficiency","Choice_3":"Macronutrient deficiencies","Question":"Foliar application is usually employed to correct","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Micronutrient deficiencies"},"Question 2":{"Choice_0":"Liquid formulation","Choice_1":"Vapor formulations","Choice_2":"Pliable fertilizer","Choice_3":"Granular fertilizer","Question":"The drill-hole method uses","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Granular fertilizer"},"Question 3":{"Choice_0":"Curb line","Choice_1":"Property line","Choice_2":"Drip line","Choice_3":"Grid line","Question":"In the drill-hole fertilizer application method, the holes should extend from near the trunk to near the","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Drip line"},"Question 4":{"Choice_0":"1 and 3 pounds (0.5 and 1.5 kg)","Choice_1":"2 and 4 pounds (1 and 2 kg)","Choice_2":"4 and 6 pounds (2 and 3 kg)","Choice_3":"6 and 8 pounds (3 and 6 kg)","Question":"Recommended application rates for quick-release fertilizers are usually between __________ of actual nitrogen per 1000 square feet (100 square meters)","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"1 and 3 pounds (0.5 and 1.5 kg)"},"Question 5":{"Choice_0":"Sulfur, potassium, and phosphorus","Choice_1":"Organic and inorganic nitrogen","Choice_2":"All 17 essential elements","Choice_3":"Nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium","Question":"A complete fertilizer contains","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium"},"Question 6":{"Choice_0":"Solar incidence","Choice_1":"Cation exchange capacity","Choice_2":"Oxygen availability","Choice_3":"Water availability","Question":"The most limiting factor in fertilizer uptake is","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Water availability"},"Question 7":{"Choice_0":"Anywhere below the drip line","Choice_1":"Representative locations around the root flare","Choice_2":"Representative locations of the area in question","Choice_3":"Anywhere the soil is moist","Question":"When taking a soil sample, several small cores should be taken from","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Representative locations of the area in question"},"Question 8":{"Choice_0":"Reduced growth","Choice_1":"Smaller than normal leaves","Choice_2":"Leaf chlorosis","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following symptoms is an indicator of nitrogen deficiency","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Leaf chlorosis"},"Question 9":{"Choice_0":"Drought symptoms are evident","Choice_1":"Specified by the client","Choice_2":"The objectives of fertilization cannot be met with slow-release fertilizers","Choice_3":"The market price for slow-release fertilizers is too high","Question":"Quick-release fertilizers should only be used when","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"The objectives of fertilization cannot be met with slow-release fertilizers"},"Question 10":{"Choice_0":"Phosphorus","Choice_1":"Sulfur","Choice_2":"Potassium","Choice_3":"Nitrogen","Question":"Which of the following is the element most likely to be deficient in trees?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Nitrogen"},"Question 11":{"Choice_0":"4","Choice_1":"6","Choice_2":"8","Choice_3":"10","Question":"A 60-pound bag of 10-6-4 fertilizer contains how many pounds of actual nitrogen?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"6"},"Question 12":{"Choice_0":"A soil salt content analysis","Choice_1":"A leaf sample analysis","Choice_2":"Laboratory analysis of soil and foliage","Choice_3":"A soil sample analysis","Question":"The most accurate way to determine a tree\u2019s nutrient needs is to obtain","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Laboratory analysis of soil and foliage"},"Question 13":{"Choice_0":"Improvement of soil structure","Choice_1":"Improvement of soil fertility","Choice_2":"Increase of biological activity","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following can be considered as a potential long-term benefit provided by organic mulches?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 14":{"Choice_0":"The presence and quantity of nutrients","Choice_1":"Soil pH","Choice_2":"Cation exchange capacity (CEC)","Choice_3":"All the above","Question":"A soil analysis gives results regarding","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All the above"},"Question 15":{"Choice_0":"Improve fertilizer uptake","Choice_1":"Decrease osmotic potential","Choice_2":"Draw moisture out of the roots","Choice_3":"Improve root growth","Question":"Excessive salinity in the root zone may","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Draw moisture out of the roots"},"Question 16":{"Choice_0":"It does not require sophisticated equipment","Choice_1":"It delivers nitrogen to the upper surface","Choice_2":"It requires the least amount of time for application","Choice_3":"Fertilizer may run off into nearby waterways","Question":"Which of the following is NOT an advantage of surface application?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Fertilizer may run off into nearby waterways"},"Question 17":{"Choice_0":"Reduce soil compaction","Choice_1":"Improve soil chemistry","Choice_2":"Greatly benefit tree health","Choice_3":"Disrupt nutrient cycling in the soil","Question":"Removing leaf litter and other natural sources of nitrogen can","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Disrupt nutrient cycling in the soil"},"Question 18":{"Choice_0":"Runoff","Choice_1":"Leaching","Choice_2":"Saturation","Choice_3":"Fertilizer burn","Question":"The washing of chemicals down through the soil is called","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Leaching"},"Question 19":{"Choice_0":"Limit the uptake of certain nutrients","Choice_1":"Influence the solubility of elements","Choice_2":"Cause nutrients to become insoluble","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Soil pH can","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Influence the solubility of elements"},"Question 20":{"Choice_0":"Lime","Choice_1":"Organic matter","Choice_2":"Sulfur","Choice_3":"Nitrogen","Question":"If the soil is too acidic, the pH can be adjusted by adding","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Lime"},"Question 21":{"Choice_0":"No one knows which levels of nutrients in soils are adequate","Choice_1":"The tests are not reliable","Choice_2":"The soil may contain adequate nutrients but something may be inhibiting uptake by the tree","Choice_3":"The nutrient content can change after collection","Question":"A soil test may not identify a nutrient deficiency problem in a plant because","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"The soil may contain adequate nutrients but something may be inhibiting uptake by the tree"},"Question 22":{"Choice_0":"It does not require sophisticated equipment","Choice_1":"It avoids dark, vigorous patches of lawn under the tree","Choice_2":"It can provide good distribution and uptake of fertilizer","Choice_3":"It requires the least amount of time for application","Question":"Which of the following is an advantage of the liquid injection method?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"It can provide good distribution and uptake of fertilizer"},"Question 23":{"Choice_0":"Damage to the cambium may result","Choice_1":"Damage to the xylem may result","Choice_2":"Repeated use can cause wounds to fuse","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Experts are cautious about recommending implants or injections because","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Damage to the cambium may result"},"Question 24":{"Choice_0":"Soil structure","Choice_1":"Soil chemistry","Choice_2":"Soil biology","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Nutrient management and prescription fertilization should consider:","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Soil chemistry"},"Question 25":{"Choice_0":"Aminonutrients","Choice_1":"Macronutrients","Choice_2":"Micronutrients","Choice_3":"Second nutrients","Question":"Which of the following do trees require in relatively large quantities?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Macronutrients"},"Question 26":{"Choice_0":"Soil amendment","Choice_1":"Nutrient leaching","Choice_2":"Excessive drainage","Choice_3":"Soil compaction","Question":"A leading cause of tree decline in urban areas is","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Soil compaction"},"Question 27":{"Choice_0":"When the ground is frozen","Choice_1":"During drought periods","Choice_2":"When application of slow-release fertilizers is suitable","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Application of fast-release, water-soluble fertilizer should be avoided:","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"During drought periods"},"Question 28":{"Choice_0":"Rate should be higher in non-restricted areas","Choice_1":"Rate should be lower in non-restricted areas","Choice_2":"Should be compensated in other areas","Choice_3":"Should not be compensated in other areas","Question":"If there is anything restricting the size of the application area, application","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Should not be compensated in other areas"},"Question 29":{"Choice_0":"Nitrogen is leached","Choice_1":"Root growth begins","Choice_2":"Dormant season begins","Choice_3":"It is needed by the tree","Question":"Fertilizer may not be readily absorbed or utilized until","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Root growth begins"},"Question 30":{"Choice_0":"Fertilizer runoff","Choice_1":"Excessive salinity","Choice_2":"Excessive osmosis","Choice_3":"Fertilizer burn","Question":"Injury to a plant resulting from excess fertilizer salts in the surrounding soil is sometimes referred to as","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Fertilizer burn"},"Question 31":{"Choice_0":"Increased","Choice_1":"Maximized","Choice_2":"Standard","Choice_3":"Decreased","Question":"Urban soils, the presence of available essential elements and microorganism activity is usually","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Decreased"},"Question 32":{"Choice_0":"The areas where iron chlorosis is evident","Choice_1":"The areas where nutrient deficiency is evident","Choice_2":"All over the tree","Choice_3":"Branches that exhibit dieback","Question":"Leaf samples for a routine foliar analysis should be taken from","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All over the tree"},"Question 33":{"Choice_0":"The lower its osmotic potential ratio (compared to sodium nitrate)","Choice_1":"The better the fertilizer","Choice_2":"The less likely plant damage will occur in case of overapplication","Choice_3":"The more likely plant damage will occur in case of overapplication","Question":"The higher the fertilizer\u2019s salt index,","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"The more likely plant damage will occur in case of overapplication"},"Question 34":{"Choice_0":"They release nutrients over an extended period of time","Choice_1":"Doing so reduces the amount of nutrients that may be leached","Choice_2":"Doing so reduces salt and fertilizer \u201cburn\u201d problems","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Especially for trees, it is desirable to use slow-release fertilizers because","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 35":{"Choice_0":"Improve fertilizer uptake","Choice_1":"Decrease osmotic potential","Choice_2":"Improve root growth","Choice_3":"Draw moisture out of the roots","Question":"Excessive salinity in the root zone may","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Draw moisture out of the roots"},"Question 36":{"Choice_0":"Nitrogen","Choice_1":"Phosphorus","Choice_2":"Macronutrients","Choice_3":"Micronutrients","Question":"Which of the following do trees require in relatively small quantities?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Micronutrients"},"Question 37":{"Choice_0":"Night crawlers","Choice_1":"Nematodes","Choice_2":"Mycorrhizae","Choice_3":"Millipedes","Question":"Some microscopic roundworms can parasitize tree roots and transmit disease, but others are known to be beneficial to trees by feeding on pathogens. These roundworms are called","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Nematodes"},"Question 38":{"Choice_0":"Restricted root growth","Choice_1":"Reduced water infiltration and availability","Choice_2":"Limited movement of oxygen and carbon dioxide in the root zone","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Soil compaction may cause","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 39":{"Choice_0":"A high water content will reduce the damaging effects","Choice_1":"Total pore space and the percentage of macropores are reduced","Choice_2":"Micropores combine to form macropores","Choice_3":"Aggregates are formed, giving the soil a better structure","Question":"When soil is compacted,","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Total pore space and the percentage of macropores are reduced"},"Question 40":{"Choice_0":"Field capacity","Choice_1":"Permanent wilting point","Choice_2":"Water-holding capacity","Choice_3":"Maximum infiltration","Question":"When gravitational water has drained from the soil, it is said to be at","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Field capacity"},"Question 41":{"Choice_0":"0 to 100","Choice_1":"-14 to +14","Choice_2":"0 to 14","Choice_3":"1 to 10","Question":"Soil pH is a measure of the acidity or alkalinity of soil with a scale ranging from","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"0 to 14"},"Question 42":{"Choice_0":"Solute","Choice_1":"Solution","Choice_2":"Sodicity","Choice_3":"Salinity","Question":"Which of the following is the term used to describe the amount of mineral ions dissolved in the soil water?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Salinity"},"Question 43":{"Choice_0":"Parent material","Choice_1":"Rhizosphere","Choice_2":"Macropores","Choice_3":"Organic layer","Question":"The zone of intense biological activity surrounding actively elongating roots is termed the","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Rhizosphere"},"Question 44":{"Choice_0":"Root growth","Choice_1":"Freezing and thawing","Choice_2":"Burrowing insects and other animals","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Soil structure develops over time as a result of","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 45":{"Choice_0":"Large amount of sand particles","Choice_1":"Small amount of clay","Choice_2":"Large percentage of micropore space","Choice_3":"Large percentage of macropore space","Question":"Soils with a high water-holding capacity contain a","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Large percentage of micropore space"},"Question 46":{"Choice_0":"45% mineral materials, 5% pore space, 50% organic matter and organisms","Choice_1":"5% mineral materials, 50% pore space, 45% organic matter and organisms","Choice_2":"5% mineral materials, 45% pore space, 50% organic matter and organisms","Choice_3":"45% mineral materials, 50% pore space, 5% organic matter and organisms","Question":"By volume, ideal soils for plant growth are composed of roughly","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"45% mineral materials, 50% pore space, 5% organic matter and organisms"},"Question 47":{"Choice_0":"The diversity of organisms living, moving and interacting in the soil","Choice_1":"An altered environment within the soil where many organisms flourish","Choice_2":"The zone of intense biological activity surrounding actively elongating roots","Choice_3":"Microscopic roundworms that feed on pathogenic, disease-causing organism","Question":"The soil food web may be defined as","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"The diversity of organisms living, moving and interacting in the soil"},"Question 48":{"Choice_0":"Genetics of the plant","Choice_1":"Available phosphorus and potassium","Choice_2":"pH of the soil","Choice_3":"available oxygen and water","Question":"The primary factor(s) in controlling the depth, spread, and tree roots are:","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"available oxygen and water"},"Question 49":{"Choice_0":"5-10 percent or less","Choice_1":"15-20 percent or less","Choice_2":"40-45 percent or more","Choice_3":"55-60 percent or more","Question":"A general guideline for incorporating organic matter into soil at an appropriate rate would be","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"5-10 percent or less"},"Question 50":{"Choice_0":"Result in poor soil aeration, negatively impacting root growth and the existence of important soil organisms","Choice_1":"Prevent the formation of girdling roots","Choice_2":"Be responsible for chemical contamination of soil","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Compaction is one of the biggest problems in urban soils because it may","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Result in poor soil aeration, negatively impacting root growth and the existence of important soil organisms"},"Question 51":{"Choice_0":"4.0-5.5","Choice_1":"6.0-6.5","Choice_2":"7.0-7.5","Choice_3":"7.5-8.0","Question":"The pH range generally favorable for most tree","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"6.0-6.5"},"Question 52":{"Choice_0":"Soil is at field capacity and all gravitational water has drained","Choice_1":"Available water is held in the root ball of a newly planted tree and absorbed by the roots as needed","Choice_2":"A tree is planted in clay soil, but is then backfilled with a more coarse soil that may act as a bowl and retain water","Choice_3":"Trees are approaching the permanent wilting point and in need of irrigation to prevent drought damage.","Question":"The term \u201cteacup effect\u201d describes a condition when","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"A tree is planted in clay soil, but is then backfilled with a more coarse soil that may act as a bowl and retain water"},"Question 53":{"Choice_0":"Mycorrhizae","Choice_1":"Compaction","Choice_2":"Poor drainage","Choice_3":"None of the above","Question":"Which of the following cannot be considered a common problem in urban soils?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Mycorrhizae"},"Question 54":{"Choice_0":"Clay, silt and organic matter","Choice_1":"Sand and clay","Choice_2":"Sand, clay, and parent material","Choice_3":"Sand, silt and clay","Question":"Soil texture refers to the relative fineness or coarseness of soil particles, or the proportions of","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Sand, silt and clay"},"Question 55":{"Choice_0":"Plants from other sites that have already transitioned to minimum irrigation should be transplanted among the new plantings","Choice_1":"Plants with varying water requirements may be grouped together as long as the irrigation schedule is varies to meet all water needs","Choice_2":"It is not necessary to estimate in advance how much water will be needed, and at what frequency, until new plantings have established root systems","Choice_3":"Plants with low water requirements and highly efficient irrigation methods should be incorporated into the plan","Question":"When planning a new landscape where minimum irrigation is used","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Plants with low water requirements and highly efficient irrigation methods should be incorporated into the plan"},"Question 56":{"Choice_0":"Anaerobic conditions","Choice_1":"Phytotoxic conditions","Choice_2":"Aerobic conditions","Choice_3":"Turgidity conditions","Question":"Tree roots may suffocate due to lack of oxygen or become damaged by a buildup of toxic compounds as a result of","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Anaerobic conditions"},"Question 57":{"Choice_0":"Transpiration rate decreases","Choice_1":"Anaerobic conditions are created","Choice_2":"Many soil organisms are killed","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"After a tree is subjected to flooded conditions","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 58":{"Choice_0":"Mature, established tree specimens require more frequent irrigation than newly transplanted trees","Choice_1":"Mature, established tree specimens may develop problems if irrigated with the same frequency as newly transplanted trees","Choice_2":"Combining newly transplanted trees on the same site with more mature, established trees should be avoided","Choice_3":"Mature, established tree specimens and newly transplanted trees with both thrive on the same irrigation schedule","Question":"When determining irrigation frequency requirements on a site where newly transplanted trees are combined with more mature trees, it is important to remember that, generally,","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Mature, established tree specimens may develop problems if irrigated with the same frequency as newly transplanted trees"},"Question 59":{"Choice_0":"Develop shallow, spreading root systems","Choice_1":"Develop mechanisms for water conservation","Choice_2":"Develop deep and extensive root systems","Choice_3":"Reduce water loss through transpiration","Question":"Frequent irrigation of drought-tolerant trees may encourage them to","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Develop shallow, spreading root systems"},"Question 60":{"Choice_0":"Inject water deep into the root zone, sometimes bypassing absorbing roots at the soil surface","Choice_1":"Are known to cause surface compaction and crusting of the top layer of the soil, and increase potential for runoff and soil erosion","Choice_2":"Apply water slowly to localized areas of the tree root zone, reducing the potential for runoff, erosion and water loss by evaporation","Choice_3":"Should be used only for irrigation of newly planted trees to distribute water into the root ball and surroundings","Question":"Drip irrigation systems","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Apply water slowly to localized areas of the tree root zone, reducing the potential for runoff, erosion and water loss by evaporation"},"Question 61":{"Choice_0":"Water-holding capacity","Choice_1":"Infiltration rate","Choice_2":"Plant and soil water loss","Choice_3":"Movement of sugar in plants","Question":"Evapotranspiration (ET) is the term for","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Plant and soil water loss"},"Question 62":{"Choice_0":"Root damage and disease","Choice_1":"Trunk injury","Choice_2":"Vascular wilt disease","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"When diagnosing the cause of a tree\u2019s drought-like symptoms, when water has been a limited factor, it is important to look for signs of","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Root damage and disease"},"Question 63":{"Choice_0":"Small, thick, leathery leaves, sometimes with sunken stomata","Choice_1":"Shallow, spreading root systems that allows them to make use of soil moisture over a great area","Choice_2":"Large, glabrous (hairless) leaves","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following are morphological adaptations of certain drought-tolerant trees may have?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Small, thick, leathery leaves, sometimes with sunken stomata"},"Question 64":{"Choice_0":"Water-holding capacity","Choice_1":"Infiltration rate","Choice_2":"Percolation rate","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following is affected by soil texture (sand, silt, and clay content)?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 65":{"Choice_0":"Amount of available water (capillary water) held in the soil","Choice_1":"Amount of water in the soil before gravitational water drains away","Choice_2":"Total amount of water held by the soil when it is at field capacity after gravitational water has drained","Choice_3":"Total amount of water moving into the soil during infiltration","Question":"Water-holding capacity of soil is defined as the","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Total amount of water held by the soil when it is at field capacity after gravitational water has drained"},"Question 66":{"Choice_0":"Hydrozoning","Choice_1":"Water budgeting","Choice_2":"Hydrophobic irrigation","Choice_3":"Compartmentalization","Question":"Grouping plants in a landscape according to their water requirements and then irrigating them by group to minimize water use is called","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Hydrozoning"},"Question 67":{"Choice_0":"Increase surface runoff","Choice_1":"Deplete gravitational water","Choice_2":"Increase macropore space","Choice_3":"Decrease macropore space","Question":"Amending the soil composition with organic materials will likely","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Increase macropore space"},"Question 68":{"Choice_0":"Infrequent, deep soakings to encourage the growth of deeper root systems","Choice_1":"Frequent, shallow watering to encourage surface rooting","Choice_2":"Watering in the afternoon to provide cooling when temperature peak","Choice_3":"None of the above","Question":"Which of the following practices will develop trees with better drought tolerance?","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Infrequent, deep soakings to encourage the growth of deeper root systems"},"Question 69":{"Choice_0":"Amending landscape soil to increase water-holding capacity","Choice_1":"Mixing plant species with varying water needs","Choice_2":"Drought-tolerant landscaping","Choice_3":"Dry season dormancy","Question":"\u2018Xeriscaping\u2019 is a commonly accepted term within the green industry to","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Drought-tolerant landscaping"},"Question 70":{"Choice_0":"Water budgeting","Choice_1":"Halophytes","Choice_2":"Drought adaptations","Choice_3":"Antitranspirants","Question":"Plant characteristics such as waxy cuticles, sunken stomata, and deep root systems are examples of","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Drought adaptations"},"Question 71":{"Choice_0":"Irrigation is not applied faster than water can infiltrate","Choice_1":"Soil aeration","Choice_2":"Plants are carefully selected to match the site\u2019s drainage conditions","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"For poorly drained soils, which of the following could be considered to avoid or ameliorate drainage-related problems","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 72":{"Choice_0":"Limited application times to match infiltration rates","Choice_1":"Ensuring the system is designed with appropriate valve and pipe sizing","Choice_2":"Using sprinkler heads with low application rates","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"When implementing a sprinkler irrigation system, water runoff and erosion can be minimized by","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 73":{"Choice_0":"Unavailable water","Choice_1":"Capillary water","Choice_2":"Gravitational water","Choice_3":"Available water","Question":"Hygroscopic water in soil is also called","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"Unavailable water"},"Question 74":{"Choice_0":"Health","Choice_1":"Growth","Choice_2":"Appearance","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Minimum irrigation provides only that amount of water needed to maintain tree","Topic":"Soil Management","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 75":{"Choice_0":"Hiding unsightly building features","Choice_1":"Light levels","Choice_2":"Drainage","Choice_3":"Soil pH","Question":"Which of the following is an example of design criteria?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Hiding unsightly building features"},"Question 76":{"Choice_0":"Circling roots","Choice_1":"Kinked roots","Choice_2":"Moist root ball","Choice_3":"Brown or black roots","Question":"Which of the following is a characteristic of healthy nursery trees?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Moist root ball"},"Question 77":{"Choice_0":"Circling roots","Choice_1":"Dried root balls","Choice_2":"Brown or black roots","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following should be avoided when selecting trees at the nursery?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 78":{"Choice_0":"A tree with foliage concentrated on the top","Choice_1":"A tree with many upright branches","Choice_2":"A tree with good branch spacing and a single trunk or leader","Choice_3":"A tree with a codominant leader","Question":"You are in the nursery selecting a large shade tree for transplant. Which of these trees is the best choice?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"A tree with good branch spacing and a single trunk or leader"},"Question 79":{"Choice_0":"Introduced species","Choice_1":"Invasive species","Choice_2":"Native species","Choice_3":"Naturalized species","Question":"A species that is indigenous to a region is known as a(n)","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Native species"},"Question 80":{"Choice_0":"Habit","Choice_1":"Variegation","Choice_2":"Adaptability","Choice_3":"Acclimation","Question":"A tree\u2019s genetic ability to adjust to different conditions is known as","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Adaptability"},"Question 81":{"Choice_0":"Adaptability","Choice_1":"Acclimation","Choice_2":"Hardiness","Choice_3":"Resistance","Question":"A tree planted in an area with low light conditions responds by developing larger, thinner leaves. This is an example of","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Acclimation"},"Question 82":{"Choice_0":"Soil conditions","Choice_1":"Light and water","Choice_2":"Growing space","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following environmental characteristics of a particular planting site would determine whether a plant would thrive?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 83":{"Choice_0":"establishes more slowly in the landscape","Choice_1":"It is more susceptible to disease","Choice_2":"It requires more maintenance","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following is a potential consequence of planting a tree that is in poor health?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 84":{"Choice_0":"Intolerance of poor soil conditions","Choice_1":"Poor fall color","Choice_2":"Weak wood","Choice_3":"Intolerance of owner neglect","Question":"Which of the following is a common negative characteristic of fast-growing trees?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Weak wood"},"Question 85":{"Choice_0":"Eucalyptus citriodora","Choice_1":"Acer platanoides \u2018Crimson King\u2019","Choice_2":"Amelanchier x grandiflora","Choice_3":"Gleditsia triacanthos var. inermis","Question":"Which of the following represents a hybrid species?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Amelanchier x grandiflora"},"Question 86":{"Choice_0":"Eucalyptus citriodora","Choice_1":"Eucalyptus","Choice_2":"citriodora","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following is a species epithet of Eucalyptus citriodora ?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"citriodora"},"Question 87":{"Choice_0":"Fraxinus (ash)","Choice_1":"Quercus (oaks)","Choice_2":"Acer (maples)","Choice_3":"Cornus (dogwoods)","Question":"Which genus of tree usually does not have an opposite leaf arrangement?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Quercus (oaks)"},"Question 88":{"Choice_0":"Pepo","Choice_1":"Nut","Choice_2":"Drupe","Choice_3":"Samara","Question":"What type of fruit does Acer produce?","Topic":"Identification and Selection","Answer":"Samara"},"Question 89":{"Choice_0":"Infrequent irrigation is recommended and necessary","Choice_1":"Frequent irrigation is neither recommended nor necessary","Choice_2":"Fertilization is neither recommended nor necessary","Choice_3":"Fertilization is needed and recommended.","Question":"Because the root system of a newly planted tree is limited, at the time of planting,","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Fertilization is neither recommended nor necessary"},"Question 90":{"Choice_0":"Photodegradable","Choice_1":"Broad in width","Choice_2":"Rigidity","Choice_3":"Nonabrasive","Question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic of a good guying material?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Photodegradable"},"Question 91":{"Choice_0":"Species and size","Choice_1":"Moisture availability","Choice_2":"Climate","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"The rate of recovery and reestablishment after planting or transplanting varies with","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 92":{"Choice_0":"Trunk wrapping","Choice_1":"Staking and guying","Choice_2":"Pruning away one-third of the crown","Choice_3":"Adequate watering","Question":"The most important step in after-planting care is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Adequate watering"},"Question 93":{"Choice_0":"Anaphylactic shock","Choice_1":"Traumatic shock","Choice_2":"Transplanting shock","Choice_3":"Transpirational shock","Question":"The stress that many trees experience after planting is commonly referred to as","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Transplanting shock"},"Question 94":{"Choice_0":"Lawn mowers","Choice_1":"Wind","Choice_2":"Vandals","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Triple staking provides protection against","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Wind"},"Question 95":{"Choice_0":"2 feet (0.6m)","Choice_1":"3 feet (0.9m)","Choice_2":"4 feet (1.2m)","Choice_3":"6 feet (1.8m)","Question":"The mulching area suggested for a 1- to 2-inch (2.5- to 5-cm) caliper tree is a circle with a diameter of at","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"6 feet (1.8m)"},"Question 96":{"Choice_0":"The tree is resistant\u2019","Choice_1":"Three growing seasons","Choice_2":"One growing season","Choice_3":"The tree is established","Question":"Support stakes or guy wires should generally be removed after","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"One growing season"},"Question 97":{"Choice_0":"Photogenic","Choice_1":"Photodegradable","Choice_2":"Photosynthate","Choice_3":"Phototropic","Question":"A material that breaks down over time when exposed to sunlight is called","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Photodegradable"},"Question 98":{"Choice_0":"1-2 inches (2-5 cm)","Choice_1":"2-4 inches (5-10cm)","Choice_2":"4-6 inches (10-15cm)","Choice_3":"6 inches (15 cm) or more","Question":"The suggested depth for mulching is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"2-4 inches (5-10cm)"},"Question 99":{"Choice_0":"15 percent","Choice_1":"25 percent","Choice_2":"40 percent","Choice_3":"50 percent","Question":"When training young trees, it is recommended that no more than __________ of the canopy is removed in any once year.","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"25 percent"},"Question 100":{"Choice_0":"Training Young Trees for Structure and Form video","Choice_1":"Best Management Practices: Tree Pruning","Choice_2":"ANSI A300 pruning standards","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Some good resources for pruning recommendations include","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 101":{"Choice_0":"Advisable","Choice_1":"Inadvisable","Choice_2":"The latest technique","Choice_3":"Mandatory","Question":"Attaching the guys above two-thirds the height of the tree is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Inadvisable"},"Question 102":{"Choice_0":"Trunk taper","Choice_1":"Foliage vigor","Choice_2":"Absorbing roots","Choice_3":"Any of the above","Question":"Staking too rigidly can have negative effects on the development of","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Absorbing roots"},"Question 103":{"Choice_0":"It works efficiently in green wood and pulls the shavings form the holes","Choice_1":"Will not rust if it gets wet from the wood","Choice_2":"Drills a hole that tapes in diameter throughout the depth of the hole","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"A ship auger (wood auger) is used for drilling hardware installation holes because","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"It works efficiently in green wood and pulls the shavings form the holes"},"Question 104":{"Choice_0":"soil and organic material to help retain water and improve structure","Choice_1":"the same type of soil that the root ball contains","Choice_2":"the same soil that was removed from the planting hole","Choice_3":"sandy loam soil to improve drainage","Question":"It is usually recommended to backfill around the tree with","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"the same soil that was removed from the planting hole"},"Question 105":{"Choice_0":"soil drainage","Choice_1":"space limitations","Choice_2":"light exposure","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"When selecting a plant species for a given site, one must consider","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 106":{"Choice_0":"stored carbohydrates and water-retention capacity","Choice_1":"a good pruning schedule","Choice_2":"addition of fertilizer to the planting hole","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"New root growth is dependent on","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"stored carbohydrates and water-retention capacity"},"Question 107":{"Choice_0":"near the surface","Choice_1":"at the bottom of the root ball","Choice_2":"from the trunk of the tree","Choice_3":"none of the above e.","Question":"After planting, the most vigorous root growth occurs","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"near the surface"},"Question 108":{"Choice_0":"support the ball from the base","Choice_1":"pull the trunk","Choice_2":"grasp several structural branches","Choice_3":"grab the sides of the burlap","Question":"When moving balled-and-burlapped trees to the planting site, the proper wa to lift them is to","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"grab the sides of the burlap"},"Question 109":{"Choice_0":"Analyze bark thickness","Choice_1":"Remove the trunk wrapping, if present","Choice_2":"Look for an intricate trunk pattern","Choice_3":"Shake it to see if it firm","Question":"During trunk inspection, it is important to","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Look for an intricate trunk pattern"},"Question 110":{"Choice_0":"Placing gravel in the bottom of the hole of provide a firm base","Choice_1":"Breaking up glazed surfaces in the hole with a hand tool","Choice_2":"Exposing the hole for long periods","Choice_3":"Filing the hole with water","Question":"If a mechanical spade is used to dig the planting hole, it is best to eliminate potential problems by","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Breaking up glazed surfaces in the hole with a hand tool"},"Question 111":{"Choice_0":"Rope","Choice_1":"Wire","Choice_2":"Plastic","Choice_3":"Any of the above","Question":"For additional support, large soil balls should be drum-laced with","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Rope"},"Question 112":{"Choice_0":"Branching structure","Choice_1":"Trunk condition","Choice_2":"Root ball condition","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"When selecting plant stock, it is important to inspect","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 113":{"Choice_0":"Compensatory pruning","Choice_1":"Pinching","Choice_2":"Root pruning","Choice_3":"Trenching","Question":"The process of pre-digging a root ball to increase the density of root development within the final ball is known as","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Trenching"},"Question 114":{"Choice_0":"Cold and dry","Choice_1":"Waterlogged","Choice_2":"Warm and moist","Choice_3":"Frozen","Question":"New root growth will be initiated earlier if the soil is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Warm and moist"},"Question 115":{"Choice_0":"Do not lift the tree by its trunk","Choice_1":"Loosely wrap the crown to minimize wind damage","Choice_2":"Pad the tree\u2019s trunk to protect it from injury","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"What measure(s) should be taken when transporting a tree to the planting site?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 116":{"Choice_0":"Sweating","Choice_1":"Perspiring","Choice_2":"Wicking","Choice_3":"Hardening off","Question":"The process used to break bud dormancy on some bare-root tree species is called","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Sweating"},"Question 117":{"Choice_0":"Stress the tree","Choice_1":"Enable soilborne pathogens to enter the trunk","Choice_2":"Drown or suffocate roots","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Excessive planting depth","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 118":{"Choice_0":"30","Choice_1":"50","Choice_2":"70","Choice_3":"90","Question":"In harvesting balled-and-burlapped trees, up to what percentage of the absorbing roots may be lost?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"90"},"Question 119":{"Choice_0":"Plant tolerant to diseases","Choice_1":"Tree species that meets site requirements","Choice_2":"Tree species that has a good branching pattern","Choice_3":"Plant tolerant of poorly drained sites","Question":"The primary factor determining the success of a planted tree is selecting a","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Tree species that meets site requirements"},"Question 120":{"Choice_0":"Fertilizer is added to the planting hole","Choice_1":"The roots be kept warm","Choice_2":"The roots be kept moist","Choice_3":"Organic matter be added to the planting hole","Question":"When planting bare-root trees, it is vital that","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"The roots be kept moist"},"Question 121":{"Choice_0":"Straighten and separate roots to reduce girdling root formation","Choice_1":"Place soften fill in the bottom of the planting hole to encourage tap root growth","Choice_2":"Backfill the hole with peat soil or organic matter to encourage root growth","Choice_3":"Always plant the container, but remove the tap portion","Question":"When planting a container-grown tree,","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Straighten and separate roots to reduce girdling root formation"},"Question 122":{"Choice_0":"Maintains moisture","Choice_1":"Reduces competition","Choice_2":"Buffers soil temperatures","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following is an advantage of mulching?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 123":{"Choice_0":"2 feet (0.6m)","Choice_1":"3 feet (0.9m)","Choice_2":"4 feet (1.2m)","Choice_3":"6 feet (1.8m)","Question":"The mulching area suggested for a 1- to 2-inch (2.5 to 5-cm) caliper tree is a circle with a diameter of at least","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"6 feet (1.8m)"},"Question 124":{"Choice_0":"general description","Choice_1":"shipping and handling of plant material","Choice_2":"plant and material requirements","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"A typical planting specification contains which section(s)?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 125":{"Choice_0":"Restrict oxygen and water availability to the roots","Choice_1":"Favor root\/trunk rot","Choice_2":"Affect soil pH","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"\u201cVolcanoes\u201d of mulch around trees can","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 126":{"Choice_0":"Definition of key terms","Choice_1":"Description of work to be done","Choice_2":"Standards and nomenclature used","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following items should be included in the general description of a planting specification?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 127":{"Choice_0":"Bare-root stock","Choice_1":"Containerized tree with loose substrate","Choice_2":"Large conifer","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following trees would be a potential candidate for stabilization?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 128":{"Choice_0":"Central leaders","Choice_1":"Permanent branches","Choice_2":"Temporary branches","Choice_3":"Scaffold branches","Question":"__________ help build trunk taper and contribute to food production, but because they will be removed later, they should not be allowed to grow to a significant diameter","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Temporary branches"},"Question 129":{"Choice_0":"Aesthetically pleasing form","Choice_1":"Lower maintenance requirements","Choice_2":"Lower potential for failure","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"One of the benefits associated with training young trees is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 130":{"Choice_0":"Pulverized rubber","Choice_1":"Geotextile fabrics","Choice_2":"Shredded bark","Choice_3":"Larva rock","Question":"All of the following are inorganic mulches except","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Shredded bark"},"Question 131":{"Choice_0":"Reinforce weak junctions or to strengthen decayed areas","Choice_1":"Heal split crotches","Choice_2":"Anchor a tree with a weak or compromised root system","Choice_3":"Drill holes for hardware installation","Question":"Bracing is used to","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Reinforce weak junctions or to strengthen decayed areas"},"Question 132":{"Choice_0":"Forms an eye-splice termination","Choice_1":"Forms a dead-end grip termination","Choice_2":"Is an unacceptable means of termination","Choice_3":"Is a weaker termination than using cable clamps","Question":"Wrapping common-grade cable around a thimble, separating the strands, and taking at least two turns per strand on the standing part of the cable","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Forms a dead-end grip termination"},"Question 133":{"Choice_0":"The tree may not produce support wood\/roots after being guyed","Choice_1":"The tree will grow around the anchor hardware","Choice_2":"Arborists rarely return to remove the guys","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Guying of mature trees is often permanent because","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"The tree may not produce support wood\/roots after being guyed"},"Question 134":{"Choice_0":"Dead-end brace","Choice_1":"Amon-eye rod","Choice_2":"Machine-threaded rod","Choice_3":"Lag-threaded rod","Question":"The type of rod that should be used in large trees, soft-wooded trees, or decayed wood is a","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Machine-threaded rod"},"Question 135":{"Choice_0":"Any length of rod can be cut to fit the branch","Choice_1":"Washers and nuts are not required to secure the end opposite the amon-eye nut","Choice_2":"They are stronger than drop-forged eye bolts","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"An advantage to using a threaded rod and an amon-eye nut as a means of anchoring a cable is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Any length of rod can be cut to fit the branch"},"Question 136":{"Choice_0":"At least 6 inches (15 cm) apart and in vertical alignment","Choice_1":"Non closer together than the distance equal to the limb diameter, or 12 inches (30cm) whichever is less","Choice_2":"More than 12 inches (30cm) apart and directly above one another","Choice_3":"As close together as practical and in the same place","Question":"When more than one cable is installed on a limb, the cables should be spaced","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Non closer together than the distance equal to the limb diameter, or 12 inches (30cm) whichever is less"},"Question 137":{"Choice_0":"Such that it bisects the imaginary line through which both branches pass","Choice_1":"Perpendicular to the larger branch and parallel to the smaller branch","Choice_2":"Perpendicular to an imaginary line that bisects that crotch","Choice_3":"Horizontal or parallel to the ground","Question":"When installing a cable directly across the crotch being supported, the cable should be positioned","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Perpendicular to an imaginary line that bisects that crotch"},"Question 138":{"Choice_0":"Limbs are larger than 8 to 10 inches (20-25cm) in diameter at the point of installation","Choice_1":"Decay is present in one or more of the limbs at the point where the hardware must be installed","Choice_2":"It would not be possible to seat the length of the lag\u2019s threads","Choice_3":"Any of the above","Question":"In which of the following situations should through-hardware, rather than lags, be used?","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Limbs are larger than 8 to 10 inches (20-25cm) in diameter at the point of installation"},"Question 139":{"Choice_0":"Strength can be achieved by cabling limbs in triangular combinations","Choice_1":"Two should be installed on each anchor , but they must be equidistant","Choice_2":"A brace rod should be installed to support each branch union","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"If multiple cables are required,","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Strength can be achieved by cabling limbs in triangular combinations"},"Question 140":{"Choice_0":"Cable grip","Choice_1":"Brace and bit","Choice_2":"Cable aid","Choice_3":"Come-along","Question":"A handy piece of equipment that can be used to spread open thimbles, tighten lags, and help wrap dead-end grips onto the cable is a","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Cable aid"},"Question 141":{"Choice_0":"Perpendicular to the pull of the cable","Choice_1":"At a 45-degree angle with the pull of the cable","Choice_2":"In direct line with the pull of the cable","Choice_3":"Perpendicular to the branch in which it is installed","Question":"Anchor hardware should be installed","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"In direct line with the pull of the cable"},"Question 142":{"Choice_0":"Heavy-duty, round washers","Choice_1":"Standard duty, round steel washers","Choice_2":"Diamond-shaped, steel washers","Choice_3":"Diamond-shaped, aluminum washers","Question":"The type of washers recommended for use in securing through-hardware is","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Heavy-duty, round washers"},"Question 143":{"Choice_0":"Minimize the number of anchors by attaching multiple cables to each anchor","Choice_1":"Only one cable should be attached to each anchor","Choice_2":"The cables must not be installed perpendicular to one another","Choice_3":"Be sure to install all the anchors in the same plane","Question":"When multiple cables are installed on a limb","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"Only one cable should be attached to each anchor"},"Question 144":{"Choice_0":"1\/4 to 1\/2 inch (6.3 to 12.7mm) smaller in diameter than the eye bolt","Choice_1":"1\/4 to 1\/2 inch (6.3 to 12.7mm) larger in diameter than the eye bolt","Choice_2":"1\/16 to 1\/8 inch (1.6 to 3.2mm) larger in diameter than the eye bolt","Choice_3":"1\/16 to 1\/8 inch (1.6 to 3.2mm) smaller in diameter than the eye bolt","Question":"Eye bolts are installed in trees through pre-drilled holes that are","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"1\/16 to 1\/8 inch (1.6 to 3.2mm) larger in diameter than the eye bolt"},"Question 145":{"Choice_0":"Support heavy limbs or limit movement of limbs with weak connections","Choice_1":"Make a potentially hazardous tree free of risk","Choice_2":"Reduce the weight of limbs to prevent failure","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Cables are installed in trees to","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 146":{"Choice_0":"7-strand, common-grade cable is both strong and stiffer","Choice_1":"EHS cable is stronger and more flexible","Choice_2":"7-strand, common-grade cable is more malleable (bendable); EHS cable is stronger","Choice_3":"EHS cable is more malleable (bendable); 7-strand, common-grade cable is stronger","Question":"Some differences between 7-strand, common-grade cable and extra-high-strength (EHS) cables are","Topic":"Installation and Establishment","Answer":"7-strand, common-grade cable is more malleable (bendable); EHS cable is stronger"},"Question 147":{"Choice_0":"voice command and response","Choice_1":"hand signals","Choice_2":"whistles","Choice_3":"any of the above","Question":"In situation in which hearing is difficult, workers may communicate with","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"hand signals"},"Question 148":{"Choice_0":"only when specified by the supervisor","Choice_1":"only when there are climbers working aloft","Choice_2":"whenever performing tree care operations","Choice_3":"only if chain saws or chippers are in use","Question":"Head protection is required for tree workers","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"whenever performing tree care operations"},"Question 149":{"Choice_0":"a mandatory requirement","Choice_1":"safety suggestions approved by ISA","Choice_2":"an advisory recommendation","Choice_3":"a regulation set down by OSHA","Question":"In ANSI safety standards, the term \u201cshall\u201d denotes","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"a mandatory requirement"},"Question 150":{"Choice_0":"reach into the infeed hopper and toss the material, make sure to let go before it contacts the rollers or blades","Choice_1":"lay the material on feed table and shove a long piece of brush in after it","Choice_2":"shove the small material through using a metal scoop shovel.","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following is acceptable for feeding small material into a chipper?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"lay the material on feed table and shove a long piece of brush in after it"},"Question 151":{"Choice_0":"protective glasses must still be worn","Choice_1":"their use is against OSHA regulations","Choice_2":"they interfere with ear muff-type hearing protection","Choice_3":"they cannot be used with protective glasses","Question":"Face shields built into hard hats offer additional face protection, but","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"protective glasses must still be worn"},"Question 152":{"Choice_0":"preventing individuals or vehicles from passing under trees while work is in progress aloft","Choice_1":"ensuring the safety of all workers","Choice_2":"using safety cones, signs, etc. to control traffic","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"It is the legal responsibility of work crews to secure the work zone, which includes","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 153":{"Choice_0":"place yourself in a safe and stable position","Choice_1":"use two means of being secured to the tree","Choice_2":"keep both hands on the saw when operating it","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"When using a chain saw in a tree, it is important to","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 154":{"Choice_0":"with the right on the trigger handle and the left hand on the upper handle","Choice_1":"the opposite of the way a right-handed person would","Choice_2":"with both hands on the trigger handle","Choice_3":"with the left hand on the trigger handle and the right hand on the upper handle","Question":"How should leaf-handed people operate a chain saw?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"with the right on the trigger handle and the left hand on the upper handle"},"Question 155":{"Choice_0":"at a 90-degree angle from the felling direction, on the side opposite the lean of the tree","Choice_1":"to the rear, directly opposite the felling direction","Choice_2":"at a 90-degree angle from the felling direction, on the side with the lean of the tree","Choice_3":"at a 45-degree angle to the rear, opposite the felling direction","Question":"The escape route the feller should take when felling a tree is","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"at a 45-degree angle to the rear, opposite the felling direction"},"Question 156":{"Choice_0":"telephone and cable TV wires","Choice_1":"underground electric lines","Choice_2":"overhead electric lines","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following should be considered energized with a potentially fatal voltage","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 157":{"Choice_0":"smoking is prohibited when handling flammable liquid","Choice_1":"flammable liquids must be stored, handled, and dispensed from approved containers","Choice_2":"equipment must not be started or operated within ten feet of the fueling site","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"To reduce the change of fires on the job site,","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 158":{"Choice_0":"The American National Standards Institute (ANSI)","Choice_1":"The International Society of Arboriculture (ISA)","Choice_2":"The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA)","Choice_3":"A committee of tree care professionals and representatives of various organization","Question":"ANSI Z133.1 standards are developed by","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"A committee of tree care professionals and representatives of various organization"},"Question 159":{"Choice_0":"feeding the butt end of the branches into the chipper first","Choice_1":"feeding material from the side of the infeed chute","Choice_2":"never placing any part of your body closer to the feed rollers, cutter wheel, or drum than the end of the infeed chute","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following are safe chipper operational practices?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 160":{"Choice_0":"the presence of electric conductors","Choice_1":"internal decay in the tree","Choice_2":"defects such as splits or dead limbs","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"When assessing the potential hazards before felling a tree, the workers should check for","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 161":{"Choice_0":"direct contact","Choice_1":"step voltage","Choice_2":"current backflow","Choice_3":"indirect contact","Question":"If any part of the body touches a conductive object that is in contact with an energized conductor, this constitutes","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"direct contact"},"Question 162":{"Choice_0":"hinging","Choice_1":"a barber chair or \u201cbarber chairing\u201d","Choice_2":"bucking","Choice_3":"kickback","Question":"Sometimes a forward-leaning tree can split vertically up from the back cut creating a dangerous situation called","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"['a barber chair or \u201cbarber chairing\u201d']"},"Question 163":{"Choice_0":"ensure that ground workers acknowledge climbers\u2019 warnings","Choice_1":"ensure that the climber warns workers below before dropping anything","Choice_2":"encourage constant communication between climbers and ground workers","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"The purpose of the voice command and response system is to","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 164":{"Choice_0":"one-third the diameter of the tree","Choice_1":"10% of the diameter of the tree","Choice_2":"80% of the diameter of the tree","Choice_3":"2 inches higher than the apex of the notch","Question":"A rule of thumb for the thickness of the hinge when felling a tree is to make it","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"10% of the diameter of the tree"},"Question 165":{"Choice_0":"failure to maintain adequate chain tension","Choice_1":"a worn sprocket or guide bar","Choice_2":"when the upper quadrant of the guide bar tip contacts an object","Choice_3":"uneven sharpening of the chain saw teeth","Question":"The situation that can cause chain saw kickback is","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"when the upper quadrant of the guide bar tip contacts an object"},"Question 166":{"Choice_0":"clear a pathway for the limbs, removing brush first","Choice_1":"plan the order of the removal to avoid being left with a limb that is too difficult or dangerous to remove","Choice_2":"try to avoid taking out a section that is too big","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"When piecing out a tree, it is important to","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"plan the order of the removal to avoid being left with a limb that is too difficult or dangerous to remove"},"Question 167":{"Choice_0":"12-strand","Choice_1":"double-braid","Choice_2":"polyester","Choice_3":"3-strand","Question":"Which type of rope is not recommended for natural-crotch rigging because the friction of the tree and the cover causes an imbalance in the load taken by the core and cover braids?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"double-braid"},"Question 168":{"Choice_0":"a false crotch takes less time to rig","Choice_1":"a false crotch allows more flexibility in placement of the rigging point","Choice_2":"no additional equipment is required when using a false crotch","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"An advantage to using a false crotch instead of a natural\u2013crotch rigging point is","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"a false crotch allows more flexibility in placement of the rigging point"},"Question 169":{"Choice_0":"topping out","Choice_1":"hinge cut","Choice_2":"drop cut","Choice_3":"snap out","Question":"The classic three-point cut used to remove limbs is also called the","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"drop cut"},"Question 170":{"Choice_0":"the rope is considered to have an adequate working load limit (WLL)","Choice_1":"the design factor has been met","Choice_2":"the rope may fail on its first use","Choice_3":"the rope may be used for climbing but not for rigging","Question":"If the load in a rope is equal to its tensile strength","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"the rope may fail on its first use"},"Question 171":{"Choice_0":"Nylon","Choice_1":"Kevlar","Choice_2":"Polyester","Choice_3":"Natural fibers","Question":"What is the most widely used construction material for arborist rope?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"Nylon"},"Question 172":{"Choice_0":"drop cut","Choice_1":"topping cut","Choice_2":"hinge cut","Choice_3":"snap cut","Question":"A cut that is handy for controlling relatively small sections of wood that may not require roping is the","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"snap cut"},"Question 173":{"Choice_0":"load the equipment up to, but not beyond, its published tensile strength","Choice_1":"establish a very small design factor such as 2 to 1","Choice_2":"a working load limit much less than the tensile strength should be established","Choice_3":"ensure that the equipment is used only for dynamic (not static) loads","Question":"To increase the life span of a rope or other piece of rigging equipment (to achieve\/gain more cycles-to-failure)","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"a working load limit much less than the tensile strength should be established"},"Question 174":{"Choice_0":"butt line","Choice_1":"tip line","Choice_2":"tagline","Choice_3":"load line","Question":"A rope tied to a piece and controlled by a ground worker, but which is neither run through a rigging point nor used for lowering, is called a","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"tagline"},"Question 175":{"Choice_0":"They are designed only for static, overhead rigging with limited loading","Choice_1":"They require a separate connecting link to secure them to the rope","Choice_2":"The side plates never extend beyond the sheave.","Choice_3":"They are heavy-duty pulleys with large, rotating sheaves.","Question":"Which of the following is true about arborist blocks?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"They are heavy-duty pulleys with large, rotating sheaves."},"Question 176":{"Choice_0":"cycles-to-failure","Choice_1":"working load limit","Choice_2":"safe lifting load","Choice_3":"breaking strength","Question":"Tensile strength divided by the design factor determines the","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"working load limit"},"Question 177":{"Choice_0":"reduced damage to the tree","Choice_1":"reduced wear on the rigging line","Choice_2":"reduce dynamic load in the rigging line","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"A potential advantage to using arborist blocks for the rigging point rather than natural crotches is","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 178":{"Choice_0":"tip-tying","Choice_1":"tag-lining","Choice_2":"balancing","Choice_3":"butt-hitching","Question":"Tying a piece above a cut and running the line through a block or crotch below the cut is known as","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"butt-hitching"},"Question 179":{"Choice_0":"carabiners must always be loaded along their major axis and never across the gate (along the minor axis)","Choice_1":"with high loads, many loading cycles, and the potential for dynamic loading, aluminum connecting links are usually the preferred choice in rigging","Choice_2":"most connectors are designed for dynamic loading and can safely be used in trunk and top removal operations","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which statement(s) about connecting links (carabiners, shackles, screw links) is true?","Topic":"Safe Work Practices","Answer":"carabiners must always be loaded along their major axis and never across the gate (along the minor axis)"},"Question 180":{"Choice_0":"terminal bud","Choice_1":"abscission zone","Choice_2":"branch bark ridge","Choice_3":"branch collar","Question":"The area at the base of the petiole where growth regulators trigger cellular changes leading to leaf drop is called the","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"abscission zone"},"Question 181":{"Choice_0":"apical buds","Choice_1":"adventitious buds","Choice_2":"lenticels","Choice_3":"nodes","Question":"The slightly enlarged portions of the twig where leaves and buds arise are called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"apical buds"},"Question 182":{"Choice_0":"Rays","Choice_1":"Included bark","Choice_2":"Internodes","Choice_3":"Buds","Question":"__________ can occur along the twig, at the base of each leaf, just under the bark, or at the tip of each twig.","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Buds"},"Question 183":{"Choice_0":"Petiole","Choice_1":"Blade","Choice_2":"Stomata","Choice_3":"Cuticle","Question":"The stalk of a leaf is known as the","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Petiole"},"Question 184":{"Choice_0":"Rays","Choice_1":"Tracheids","Choice_2":"Sieve cells","Choice_3":"Companion cells","Question":"Small layers parenchyma cells that extend across the phloem and xylem are called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Rays"},"Question 185":{"Choice_0":"Heartwood","Choice_1":"Cambium","Choice_2":"Phloem","Choice_3":"Xylem","Question":"Movement of sugar in the __________ is slow, moving across pressure gradients, and requiring energy.","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Phloem"},"Question 186":{"Choice_0":"Vessels","Choice_1":"Parenchyma","Choice_2":"Cambium","Choice_3":"Phloem","Question":"The secondary, also called lateral, meristem that produces the phloem and xylem tissues and is responsible for growth in diameter is called the","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Cambium"},"Question 187":{"Choice_0":"Sinker roots","Choice_1":"Lateral roots","Choice_2":"Mycorrhizae","Choice_3":"Absorbing roots","Question":"The term given to the symbiotic relationships between roots and certain fungi is","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Mycorrhizae"},"Question 188":{"Choice_0":"Gymnosperm","Choice_1":"Bark","Choice_2":"Lenticel","Choice_3":"Sapwood","Question":"__________ is the protective tissue covering a tree\u2019s branches and stems that moderates temperatures, reduces water loss and protects against injury.","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Bark"},"Question 189":{"Choice_0":"Nitrogen accumulates in the upper few inches","Choice_1":"Roots grow where moisture and oxygen are available","Choice_2":"They cannot penetrate the compacted soil that is deeper","Choice_3":"Mycorrhizae are available as nourishment near the surface","Question":"Most of the fine, absorbing roots of trees are found in the upper few inches of soil because","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Roots grow where moisture and oxygen are available"},"Question 190":{"Choice_0":"The absorption of light for photosynthesis","Choice_1":"Absorption of water minerals","Choice_2":"Production of vascular elements","Choice_3":"The downward growth of roots","Question":"In mycorrhizae, the fungi derive nourishment from the tree while aiding in the","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Absorption of water minerals"},"Question 191":{"Choice_0":"Meristems","Choice_1":"Vessels","Choice_2":"Cambium","Choice_3":"Phloem","Question":"The xylem of gymnosperms( pines, spruces, firs, etc.) has tracheids, fibers, and parenchyma cells, but lacks","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Vessels"},"Question 192":{"Choice_0":"Parenchyma","Choice_1":"Tracheids","Choice_2":"Vessels","Choice_3":"Fibers","Question":"Living cells in the outer layers of xylem that store carbohydrates, help defend against decay, and are active in water conduction are called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Parenchyma"},"Question 193":{"Choice_0":"Lenticels","Choice_1":"Rays","Choice_2":"Stomata","Choice_3":"Sieve tube elements","Question":"Small openings in the bark that permit the exchange of gases are called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Lenticels"},"Question 194":{"Choice_0":"Carbohydrates","Choice_1":"Internodes","Choice_2":"Heartwood","Choice_3":"Lenticels","Question":"Each branch of a tree is generally autonomous, producing enough __________ to sustain itself.","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Carbohydrates"},"Question 195":{"Choice_0":"Cambium","Choice_1":"Apical","Choice_2":"Cork cambium","Choice_3":"Axial","Question":"Primary meristem tissue found in buds and root tips called __________ meristem.","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Apical"},"Question 196":{"Choice_0":"Regulates the opening and closing of stomata in response to environmental conditions","Choice_1":"Protect the stem where the leaf has fallen from desiccation and pathogen entry","Choice_2":"Is the meristematic point where new buds will develop if triggered by growth regulators","Choice_3":"Minimize excess water loss from the surface cells of the leaf","Question":"In additional to enabling leaf drop, the abscission zone also","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Protect the stem where the leaf has fallen from desiccation and pathogen entry"},"Question 197":{"Choice_0":"Guard cells","Choice_1":"Carotenoids","Choice_2":"Chloroplasts","Choice_3":"Lenticels","Question":"__________ regulate the opening and closing of stomata in response to environmental stimuli such as light, temperature, and humidity","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Guard cells"},"Question 198":{"Choice_0":"Leaf drop","Choice_1":"Photosynthesis","Choice_2":"Transpiration","Choice_3":"Fall color","Question":"In deciduous trees, the breakdown of chlorophyll and the expression of other pigments in the leaves results in","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Fall color"},"Question 199":{"Choice_0":"Sunlight","Choice_1":"Phototropism","Choice_2":"Cytokinin","Choice_3":"Energy","Question":"In phloem transport, the carbohydrate products of photosynthesis are actively pumped through the phloem, a process that requires","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Energy"},"Question 200":{"Choice_0":"Differentiation","Choice_1":"Transpiration","Choice_2":"Translocation","Choice_3":"Respiration","Question":"The process by which chemical energy generated by photosynthesis is used by the tree is called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Respiration"},"Question 201":{"Choice_0":"Carotenoids","Choice_1":"Auxin","Choice_2":"Anthocyanins","Choice_3":"Cytokinin","Question":"Produced in roots, __________ is instrumental in shoot initiation and growth","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Cytokinin"},"Question 202":{"Choice_0":"Carotenoids","Choice_1":"Cytokinin","Choice_2":"Anthocyanins","Choice_3":"Auxin","Question":"Produced primarily in shoot tips, __________ plays an important role in root development","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Auxin"},"Question 203":{"Choice_0":"Antitranspirants","Choice_1":"Plant hormones","Choice_2":"Meristems","Choice_3":"Tropism","Question":"The coordination of processes in trees is controlled in part by naturally occurring compounds referred to as","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Plant hormones"},"Question 204":{"Choice_0":"Oxygen","Choice_1":"Carbon dioxide","Choice_2":"Starch","Choice_3":"Sugars","Question":"What photosynthesis byproduct is released through the stomata","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Oxygen"},"Question 205":{"Choice_0":"Chloroplasts","Choice_1":"Carbohydrates","Choice_2":"Mycorrhizae","Choice_3":"Photosynthate","Question":"During photosynthesis, light energy is absorbed and trapped in the","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Chloroplasts"},"Question 206":{"Choice_0":"Cambium","Choice_1":"Phloem","Choice_2":"Xylem","Choice_3":"Pith","Question":"Most photosynthate is either stored or utilized for growth and plant functions in close proximity to where it is produced, but it is also transported through the __________ for use or storage in the roots and other plant parts","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Phloem"},"Question 207":{"Choice_0":"Radial transport","Choice_1":"Translocation","Choice_2":"Axial transport","Choice_3":"Compartmentalization","Question":"The process by which trees limit the spread of discoloration and decay is called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Compartmentalization"},"Question 208":{"Choice_0":"Translocation of sugar in the phloem","Choice_1":"Production of sugar using light energy in photosynthesis","Choice_2":"Evaporation of water from leaves","Choice_3":"Burning of stored starches in respiration","Question":"The transpirational pull that helps move water up through the xylem is created by the","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Evaporation of water from leaves"},"Question 209":{"Choice_0":"May move out of the roots and into the soil","Choice_1":"Absorption by the roots increases","Choice_2":"May be saturated in the root cells","Choice_3":"Movement in the soil stops because absorption sites are occupied","Question":"When salt concentrations in the soil are high, such as from deicing salts or excessive fertilization, water","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"May move out of the roots and into the soil"},"Question 210":{"Choice_0":"Lenticel","Choice_1":"Sapwood","Choice_2":"Phloem","Choice_3":"Mycorrhizae","Question":"The __________ is composed of sieve cells in gymnosperms and sieve tube elements in angiosperms","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Phloem"},"Question 211":{"Choice_0":"Symbiosis","Choice_1":"Osmosis","Choice_2":"Axial transport","Choice_3":"Transpiration","Question":"The movement of water through a membrane from a region of high water potential to low water potential is called","Topic":"Tree Biology","Answer":"Osmosis"},"Question 212":{"Choice_0":"Remove interior foliage shaded by the outside branches","Choice_1":"Remove the least vigorous branches from the outside of the canopy","Choice_2":"Never prune live branches from a root-damaged tree","Choice_3":"Remove live branches in proportion to estimated root loss","Question":"One good way to prune a healthy medium-aged tree that has sustained root damage from construction equipment would be to:","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Remove the least vigorous branches from the outside of the canopy"},"Question 213":{"Choice_0":"Decayed roots near the trunk","Choice_1":"Codominant stems","Choice_2":"Dense canopy shading turf below","Choice_3":"Cracks in large limbs and branches","Question":"Which of the following faults or tree defects are partially correctable in vigorous mature trees?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Dense canopy shading turf below"},"Question 214":{"Choice_0":"Remove dead branches only","Choice_1":"Remove live branches to help develop good, strong structure","Choice_2":"Remove live branches from the end of an aggressive, low limb","Choice_3":"Shorten some branches to space main limbs along the trunk","Question":"Which of the following would be LEAST appropriate in young trees?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Remove dead branches only"},"Question 215":{"Choice_0":"Remove dead branches only","Choice_1":"Thin some live branches from the edge of the canopy to reduce wind resistance","Choice_2":"Remove live branches from the end of a long, low limb","Choice_3":"Reduce the canopy to increase light to turf below","Question":"Which of the following would be LEAST appropriate in mature trees?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Reduce the canopy to increase light to turf below"},"Question 216":{"Choice_0":"Tree falls over with climber in it due to root problems","Choice_1":"Tree splits at point of included bark","Choice_2":"Decayed area on a branch breaks","Choice_3":"Safety rope fails","Question":"What is one of the leading causes of climber injury and death when working in trees?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Decayed area on a branch breaks"},"Question 217":{"Choice_0":"If a wound dressing is used, it should be a product that is phytotoxic","Choice_1":"Wound dressings accelerate closure and compartmentalization of wounds","Choice_2":"Research does not support the use of wound dressings to reduce decay","Choice_3":"Wound dressings increase the incidence of oak wilt infection","Question":"Which of the following statements about wound dressings is true?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Research does not support the use of wound dressings to reduce decay"},"Question 218":{"Choice_0":"Subordinated stems","Choice_1":"Permanent branches","Choice_2":"Watersprouts","Choice_3":"Codominant stems","Question":"When two stems of approximately equal size arise from a union, __________ are created and a branch collar does not form.","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Codominant stems"},"Question 219":{"Choice_0":"The pruning of large, mature trees is usually limited to the removal of dead branches or to reduce the severity of structural defects.","Choice_1":"Smaller cuts close and compartmentalize faster than larger cuts","Choice_2":"Every pruning cut has the potential to change the growth of a tree","Choice_3":"Mature trees are more tolerant of heavy pruning than juvenile trees","Question":"Which of the following is NOT a true statement?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Mature trees are more tolerant of heavy pruning than juvenile trees"},"Question 220":{"Choice_0":"Percolation","Choice_1":"Desiccation","Choice_2":"Infiltration","Choice_3":"Compartmentalization","Question":"The natural process of defense in trees by which they wall off decay in the wood is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Compartmentalization"},"Question 221":{"Choice_0":"Watersprouts","Choice_1":"Included bark","Choice_2":"The branch collar","Choice_3":"The branch protection zone","Question":"If __________ develops inside the union of two branches, the branch union will be weakened.","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Included bark"},"Question 222":{"Choice_0":"Deplete these reserves and reduce the stability of the tree to produce more energy through photosynthesis","Choice_1":"Shut down the photosynthetic process in remaining branches","Choice_2":"Cause all energy storage to revert the roots","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Because some energy reserves are stored in branches, excessive branch removal will","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Deplete these reserves and reduce the stability of the tree to produce more energy through photosynthesis"},"Question 223":{"Choice_0":"10","Choice_1":"25","Choice_2":"35","Choice_3":"40","Question":"Although young trees are often tolerant of severe pruning, the goal should be to remove no more than __________ percent of the canopy in any one year.","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"25"},"Question 224":{"Choice_0":"Causes an immediate increase in root growth to take up food","Choice_1":"Restricts respiration and transpiration in the remaining foliage","Choice_2":"Upsets the tree\u2019s well-developed shoot-to-root ratio and dramatically reduces its capacity to produce photosynthate","Choice_3":"With divert energy reserves to increase the production of heartwood tissue","Question":"Often, topping removes so much of the crown of a mature tree that it","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Upsets the tree\u2019s well-developed shoot-to-root ratio and dramatically reduces its capacity to produce photosynthate"},"Question 225":{"Choice_0":"Provide clearance","Choice_1":"Reduce shade and wind resistance","Choice_2":"Maintain health","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following is a stated objective for pruning trees?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 226":{"Choice_0":"Size and abundance of flowers","Choice_1":"Size of fruit","Choice_2":"Abundance of fruit","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Timing and choice of pruning cuts can influence the","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Abundance of fruit"},"Question 227":{"Choice_0":"Reduce the risk of failure","Choice_1":"Reduce shade and wind resistance","Choice_2":"Influence flower or fruit production","Choice_3":"Improve a view","Question":"A pruning program designed to create structurally sound trunk and branch architecture will meet the objective to","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Reduce shade and wind resistance"},"Question 228":{"Choice_0":"Do not have a branch bark ridge or collar","Choice_1":"Are never thinned, subordinated, or reduced","Choice_2":"Develop as codominants to the central leader","Choice_3":"Remain smaller than half the diameter of the parent branch","Question":"Research suggests that the branch protection zone forms best on branches that","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Remain smaller than half the diameter of the parent branch"},"Question 229":{"Choice_0":"Topping","Choice_1":"Reduction","Choice_2":"Lion tailing","Choice_3":"Vista pruning","Question":"The reduction of a tree\u2019s size using heading cuts that shorten limbs or branches back to a predetermined crown limit is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Reduction"},"Question 230":{"Choice_0":"Varies with the disease, the tools, and the conditions","Choice_1":"Is probably rare","Choice_2":"May be mitigated by tool sterilization","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"The probability of spreading pathogens on pruning tools","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Varies with the disease, the tools, and the conditions"},"Question 231":{"Choice_0":"Branch collar","Choice_1":"Branch union","Choice_2":"Branch bark ridge","Choice_3":"Branch protection zone","Question":"The areas where a branch joins another branch or trunk created by the overlapping branch or trunk wood, or xylem tissues, is called the","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Branch bark ridge"},"Question 232":{"Choice_0":"Well before bud break","Choice_1":"Just after a growth flush","Choice_2":"Immediately after leaves fall from the tree in fall or early winter","Choice_3":"During the dormant period","Question":"If your objective is to slow growth, prune","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Just after a growth flush"},"Question 233":{"Choice_0":"Overlapping branch and trunk wood","Choice_1":"Confluence of the branch bark ridge","Choice_2":"Growth around included bark","Choice_3":"The branch protection zone","Question":"The branch collar is formed by","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Overlapping branch and trunk wood"},"Question 234":{"Choice_0":"Pruning wounds that bleed (drain sap) will not close or compartmentalize properly","Choice_1":"Although unattractive, research has shown that sap drainage (bleeding) has little negative effect on tree growth","Choice_2":"Bleeding from pruning wounds depletes sap reserves and leads to disease problems","Choice_3":"The tree\u2019s growth will be reduce significantly due to the loss of sap form the \u2018bleeding\u2019 of the pruning wounds","Question":"When pruning certain species of trees, such as maples (Acer spp. ) and birches (Betula spp. ) in the early spring when sap flow is heavy, arborists should know that","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Although unattractive, research has shown that sap drainage (bleeding) has little negative effect on tree growth"},"Question 235":{"Choice_0":"Conifers lack a branch protection zone","Choice_1":"Branch reduction can cause double leaders to develop","Choice_2":"Few conifers have the capability to produce new shoots on old wood","Choice_3":"Conifer never develop codominant stems","Question":"Severe branch reduction on most conifers should be avoided because","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Conifers lack a branch protection zone"},"Question 236":{"Choice_0":"Pollarding","Choice_1":"Restoration","Choice_2":"Heading","Choice_3":"Espalier","Question":"The specialty pruning type that involves removing all shoots every one or two years back to the same position on the tree is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Pollarding"},"Question 237":{"Choice_0":"Espalier","Choice_1":"Pollarding","Choice_2":"Vista pruning","Choice_3":"Intermodal cuts","Question":"A combination of cutting and training branches that are oriented vertically in one plane, usually supported on a wall, fence, or trellis is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Espalier"},"Question 238":{"Choice_0":"Lateral branch large enough to assume the terminal role (apical dominance)","Choice_1":"Parent branch or trunk","Choice_2":"Tertiary branch no more than one-third the diameter","Choice_3":"Branch collar, without cutting stem tissue","Question":"When making a reduction cut, the cut should be made to a","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Lateral branch large enough to assume the terminal role (apical dominance)"},"Question 239":{"Choice_0":"Thinning","Choice_1":"Crown cleaning","Choice_2":"Lion tailing","Choice_3":"Reduction","Question":"The most common, routine pruning technique for landscape tree is","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Crown cleaning"},"Question 240":{"Choice_0":"45 degrees","Choice_1":"60 degrees","Choice_2":"75 degrees","Choice_3":"90 degrees","Question":"When pruning palms, if fronds must be removed, avoid removing fronds that initiate at an angle of __________ or greater above horizontal","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"45 degrees"},"Question 241":{"Choice_0":"Scaffold branches","Choice_1":"Temporary branches","Choice_2":"Codominant branches","Choice_3":"Leaders","Question":"__________ should be selected for strong attachment, appropriate size, and adequate spacing in relation to other branches.","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Scaffold branches"},"Question 242":{"Choice_0":"Thinning","Choice_1":"Reduction","Choice_2":"Cleaning","Choice_3":"Vista pruning","Question":"What pruning technique is done to increase light penetration and air-movement by reducing crown density?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Thinning"},"Question 243":{"Choice_0":"Overthinning or lion tailing","Choice_1":"The need for crown reduction","Choice_2":"Insufficient crown cleaning","Choice_3":"Pollarding","Question":"Vigorous production of watersprouts on interior limbs is often a sign of","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Overthinning or lion tailing"},"Question 244":{"Choice_0":"Espaliered","Choice_1":"Subordinated or removed","Choice_2":"Lion-tailed","Choice_3":"Pollarded","Question":"When training young trees and selecting a dominant leader, competing stems should be","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Subordinated or removed"},"Question 245":{"Choice_0":"USDA Best Management Practices","Choice_1":"US Forest Service Pruning Standards","Choice_2":"ANSI A300 Pruning","Choice_3":"OSHA 1910.269","Question":"What are the standards for utility pruning in the United States?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"ANSI A300 Pruning"},"Question 246":{"Choice_0":"Crown restoration","Choice_1":"Cleaning","Choice_2":"Structural pruning","Choice_3":"Thinning","Question":"The selective removal of dead, diseased, and\/or broken branches is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Cleaning"},"Question 247":{"Choice_0":"Structural pruning","Choice_1":"Reduction","Choice_2":"Cleaning","Choice_3":"Restoration","Question":"Selective removal or deduction of branches, sprouts, and stubs on trees that have been topped, vandalized, or damaged in a storm is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Restoration"},"Question 248":{"Choice_0":"Make the cut at an imaginary, perpendicular line that bisects that union","Choice_1":"Cut as close to the parent branch as possible without cutting the collar or leaving a stub","Choice_2":"Cut away from the branch bark ridge and toward the parent stem","Choice_3":"Always cut to a lateral large enough to assume the terminal role","Question":"When removing a branch at its point of origin","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Make the cut at an imaginary, perpendicular line that bisects that union"},"Question 249":{"Choice_0":"Begin with a top cut and finish with an undercut","Choice_1":"Use the three cut technique, which removes most of the weight before making the final cut","Choice_2":"Thin the branch before removing it","Choice_3":"Prune in the dormant season when the sap is not flowing","Question":"To prevent bark stripping down the trunk while removing a main branch from the trunk","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Use the three cut technique, which removes most of the weight before making the final cut"},"Question 250":{"Choice_0":"Crown reduction","Choice_1":"Pollarding","Choice_2":"Crown raising","Choice_3":"Topping","Question":"__________ is best accomplished by cutting limbs back to laterals capable of sustaining the remaining limb and assuming apical dominance","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Crown reduction"},"Question 251":{"Choice_0":"Clearly defined pruning objectives","Choice_1":"Size specifications for branches to be removed (or not removed)","Choice_2":"The pruning types to be performed to meet the objectives","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Among other things, pruning specifications should include","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 252":{"Choice_0":"Crown raising","Choice_1":"Utility pruning","Choice_2":"Vista pruning","Choice_3":"Crown reduction","Question":"The selective removal or reduction of scaffold limbs to allow a specific view from a predetermined point is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Crown reduction"},"Question 253":{"Choice_0":"The loss of service","Choice_1":"Damage to utility equipment","Choice_2":"Impairment of facilities","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"What potential problem does utility pruning prevent?","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 254":{"Choice_0":"Reduction","Choice_1":"Lion tailing","Choice_2":"Restoration","Choice_3":"Pollarding","Question":"The removal of an excessive number of inner laterals and foliage is called","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Lion tailing"},"Question 255":{"Choice_0":"Pruning a tree to remove a defective part","Choice_1":"Moving a picnic table to reduce the target value","Choice_2":"Limited access to the area around a tree","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"An example of a risk abatement action is","Topic":"Pruning","Answer":"Pruning a tree to remove a defective part"},"Question 256":{"Choice_0":"Maintenance, growth, water uptake, and defense","Choice_1":"Maintenance, transpiration, storage, and defense","Choice_2":"Maintenance, growth, storage, and defense","Choice_3":"Maintenance, growth, storage, and fall color","Question":"Tree allocates energy to which four primary functions?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Maintenance, growth, storage, and defense"},"Question 257":{"Choice_0":"Leaf hairs","Choice_1":"Cacti spikes","Choice_2":"Rose thorns","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following is an example of a physical defense mechanism against plant-eating insects or other animals?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 258":{"Choice_0":"Nonliving factor","Choice_1":"Biotic agent","Choice_2":"Environmental factor","Choice_3":"Abiotic agent","Question":"Non-uniform damage patterns may be an indication that the disorder is caused by a(n)","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Biotic agent"},"Question 259":{"Choice_0":"Signs and symptoms","Choice_1":"Plant species affects","Choice_2":"Type of damage observed","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"When diagnosing a biotic disorder, it is important to take which of the following into consideration?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 260":{"Choice_0":"Adding sulfur to lower the soil pH around an ailing tree","Choice_1":"Cabling and bracing two codominant stems that are starting to split","Choice_2":"Vertical mulching around an ailing tree to relieve compaction damage","Choice_3":"Training a young tree to establish proper form","Question":"An example of proactive management of a tree within the landscape is","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Training a young tree to establish proper form"},"Question 261":{"Choice_0":"A pathogenic organism","Choice_1":"An insect vector","Choice_2":"A susceptible host","Choice_3":"An environment suitable for disease development","Question":"Which of the following is NOT one of the tree conditions needs in order for a tree to become diseased?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"An insect vector"},"Question 262":{"Choice_0":"Deal effectively with environmental conditions","Choice_1":"Genetically adapt to environmental conditions","Choice_2":"Put on new growth within one year","Choice_3":"Produce prolific seeds","Question":"Vitality is often defined as a plant\u2019s ability to","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Deal effectively with environmental conditions"},"Question 263":{"Choice_0":"Limbs and branches","Choice_1":"Roots and root collar","Choice_2":"Foliage","Choice_3":"Trunk","Question":"In the diagnostic process, what is the most frequently overlooked portions of the tree?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Roots and root collar"},"Question 264":{"Choice_0":"Carefully examine the site","Choice_1":"Accurately identify the plant","Choice_2":"Distinguish signs from symptoms","Choice_3":"Define the problem as biotic or abiotic","Question":"In diagnosing a plant problem, what is the first step that should be taken to quickly limit the number of suspected causes?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Define the problem as biotic or abiotic"},"Question 265":{"Choice_0":"Trunk flare","Choice_1":"Sunscald","Choice_2":"Vandalism","Choice_3":"Physical damage","Question":"In an area around a tree that is frequently mowed, an arborist removed the turf grass and replaced it with mulch. What type of problem was the arborist trying to prevent?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Physical damage"},"Question 266":{"Choice_0":"Nicotine","Choice_1":"Lignin","Choice_2":"A lipid","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"An example of a chemical defense compound that has been used as a natural pesticide is","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Nicotine"},"Question 267":{"Choice_0":"A sign","Choice_1":"A symptom","Choice_2":"Diagnosis","Choice_3":"Necrosis","Question":"The physical evidence of a causal agent is called","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"A sign"},"Question 268":{"Choice_0":"Early leaf drop","Choice_1":"Excessive production of terminal shoots","Choice_2":"Skeletonized leaves","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Which of the following symptoms is associated with chronic water stress?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Early leaf drop"},"Question 269":{"Choice_0":"Planting in sandy soils","Choice_1":"Soil compaction","Choice_2":"Deep planting","Choice_3":"Excessive watering","Question":"All of the following wound likely lead to anaerobic conditions within the root zone except :","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Planting in sandy soils"},"Question 270":{"Choice_0":"Witch\u2019s broom","Choice_1":"Scorch","Choice_2":"Stunting","Choice_3":"Dieback","Question":"The condition in which branches in the tree crown die from the tips toward the center is called:","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Dieback"},"Question 271":{"Choice_0":"When designing the landscape and selecting plants","Choice_1":"Once a conflict between vegetation and planting site has been identified","Choice_2":"Once plants have become established within the landscape","Choice_3":"At the first sign of a pest infestation or decline in health","Question":"Ideally, Plant Health Care should begin","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"When designing the landscape and selecting plants"},"Question 272":{"Choice_0":"Light availability","Choice_1":"Soil characteristics","Choice_2":"Water availability","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"When examining the site in which a declining tree is found, it is important to take into consideration","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 273":{"Choice_0":"Gall","Choice_1":"Canker","Choice_2":"Chlorosis","Choice_3":"Rust","Question":"A localized diseased area, often shrunken and discolored, on stems and branches is called","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Canker"},"Question 274":{"Choice_0":"Individual clients differ in their pest management expectations","Choice_1":"Little is known about the biology of many common pests","Choice_2":"Pest populations vary year to year","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Past attempts to create standardized action thresholds for common pests have been largely unsuccessful because","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 275":{"Choice_0":"Plant information","Choice_1":"Site information","Choice_2":"Disorder information","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"What information should be collected during a landscape inspection?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 276":{"Choice_0":"Plant value, pesticide application rate, and method of application","Choice_1":"Pest damage potential, time of year, and pesticide application rate","Choice_2":"Pest damage potential, time of year, and plant value","Choice_3":"Time of year, pesticide application rate, and method of application","Question":"When establishing an action threshold, it is important to consider","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Pest damage potential, time of year, and plant value"},"Question 277":{"Choice_0":"Competes with desirable plants for resources","Choice_1":"Threatens the health, structural integrity, or appearance of desirable plants","Choice_2":"Diminishes personal enjoyment, utility, or safety in the landscape","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"A landscape pest is any organism that","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 278":{"Choice_0":"Physiological action threshold","Choice_1":"Cost action threshold","Choice_2":"Aesthetic action threshold","Choice_3":"Visual action threshold","Question":"The point at which action must be taken to prevent intolerable visual damage to a landscape plant is known as","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Aesthetic action threshold"},"Question 279":{"Choice_0":"Prevention, suppression, and eradication","Choice_1":"Eradication and suppression","Choice_2":"Prevention and eradication","Choice_3":"Prevention and suppression","Question":"In most cases, IPM focuses on pest","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Prevention and suppression"},"Question 280":{"Choice_0":"A situation in which tree health is in jeopardy","Choice_1":"A situation in which a tree\u2019s appearance in negatively affected","Choice_2":"A situation in which a pest becomes a nuisance.","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Depending on the client, which of the following could be a threshold that would warrant pest management intervention?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"A situation in which a tree\u2019s appearance in negatively affected"},"Question 281":{"Choice_0":"Patience","Choice_1":"The use of chemical pesticides","Choice_2":"The presence of beneficial insects","Choice_3":"Monitoring","Question":"The key to the success of any PHC program is","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Monitoring"},"Question 282":{"Choice_0":"Usually can be achieved with limited applications of low-toxicity pesticides","Choice_1":"Does not require monitoring","Choice_2":"Prevents pest occurrence","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"One reason suppression is often preferred over eradication is it","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Usually can be achieved with limited applications of low-toxicity pesticides"},"Question 283":{"Choice_0":"Pomology","Choice_1":"Phenology","Choice_2":"Life stage","Choice_3":"Degree days","Question":"The study of relationship between periodic biological events and climatic change is called","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Phenology"},"Question 284":{"Choice_0":"Advanced reconnaissance procedure (ARP)","Choice_1":"Plant Health Criteria (PHC)","Choice_2":"Appropriate Response Process (ARP)","Choice_3":"Action Threshold (AT)","Question":"The process of gathering information, assessing the problem, determining client expectations, and deciding what action is needed is called","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Action Threshold (AT)"},"Question 285":{"Choice_0":"Highly susceptible to disorders","Choice_1":"The main focus of a particular landscape","Choice_2":"Of significance (financially, historically, emotionally) to the home owner","Choice_3":"Any of the above","Question":"A key plant is any plant that is","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Any of the above"},"Question 286":{"Choice_0":"Pest population level","Choice_1":"Pest life stage","Choice_2":"Pest type","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"If a potential pest is discovered during a landscape inspection, what information should be collected?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 287":{"Choice_0":"Regional pests","Choice_1":"Primary pests","Choice_2":"Cyclical pests","Choice_3":"Key pests","Question":"Organisms that are frequently encountered in a region and predictably cause injury to landscape plants are known as","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Key pests"},"Question 288":{"Choice_0":"Stress","Choice_1":"Acclimation","Choice_2":"Suppression","Choice_3":"Resistance","Question":"A factor that negatively affects tree health and that may stimulate a response is called","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Stress"},"Question 289":{"Choice_0":"Quarantine","Choice_1":"Sanitation","Choice_2":"Suppression","Choice_3":"Removal","Question":"The act of removing infested plant parts (fallen twigs, leaves and fruit) from a landscape in an effort to prevent a buildup of a pest population is known as","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Sanitation"},"Question 290":{"Choice_0":"Improve plant growth conditions and discourage conditions that are favorable to pest development","Choice_1":"Prevent preferred host plants from growing and use cost effective and environmentally sound means of suppression pest populations","Choice_2":"Use chemicals to reduce pest populations and associated plant injury to a tolerable level","Choice_3":"Apply both fertilizers and pesticides in manner that accomplishes management goals while minimizing environmental impact.","Question":"Two key aspects of pest prevention in the landscape are","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Improve plant growth conditions and discourage conditions that are favorable to pest development"},"Question 291":{"Choice_0":"Man-made or naturally occurring","Choice_1":"Used to disrupt insect molting and growth processes","Choice_2":"Used to make insect adult sterile","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Insect growth regulators are","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Used to disrupt insect molting and growth processes"},"Question 292":{"Choice_0":"Faster and less consistent","Choice_1":"Slower and more consistent","Choice_2":"Slower and less consistent","Choice_3":"Faster and more consistent","Question":"Compared to chemical pesticide treatments, augmentation is generally","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Slower and less consistent"},"Question 293":{"Choice_0":"Dormant oil","Choice_1":"Microbial pesticide","Choice_2":"Insect growth regulator","Choice_3":"Botanical pesticide","Question":"Bacillus thuringiensis (Bt) is an example of a","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Microbial pesticide"},"Question 294":{"Choice_0":"Biohazardous products","Choice_1":"Biomedical control products","Choice_2":"Biorational control products","Choice_3":"Biological warfare products","Question":"Insecticidal soaps, horticultural oils, botanicals, and insect growth regulators are examples of","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Biorational control products"},"Question 295":{"Choice_0":"Pest reduction","Choice_1":"Pest resurgence","Choice_2":"Eradication","Choice_3":"Aftershock","Question":"This may occur if a pest species recovers from a broad-spectrum pesticide application faster than its natural enemies","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Pest resurgence"},"Question 296":{"Choice_0":"Systemic","Choice_1":"Transgenic","Choice_2":"Contact","Choice_3":"Systematic","Question":"A pesticide that is absorbed in a plant and tgransported through its vascular system is considered","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Systemic"},"Question 297":{"Choice_0":"Importation","Choice_1":"Introduction","Choice_2":"Conservation","Choice_3":"Augmentation","Question":"The release of non-native natural enemies into the landscape in a effort to control a pest is called.","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Introduction"},"Question 298":{"Choice_0":"Parasite","Choice_1":"Saprophyte","Choice_2":"Predator","Choice_3":"Pathogen","Question":"An organism that lives in or on a host organism, deriving nourishment from the host at its expense, is known as a","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Parasite"},"Question 299":{"Choice_0":"They must be applied directly to the pest to be effective","Choice_1":"They have a relatively narrow spectrum","Choice_2":"They have very low toxicity","Choice_3":"They have long-lasting residual effects","Question":"There are many advantages in using insecticidal soaps and horticultural oils. Which of the following is considered a disadvantage?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"They have a relatively narrow spectrum"},"Question 300":{"Choice_0":"Foliar spray","Choice_1":"Trunk injection","Choice_2":"Soil drench","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Systemic pesticides can enter a plant\u2019s vascular system through which type of application?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Trunk injection"},"Question 301":{"Choice_0":"Conservation","Choice_1":"Introduction","Choice_2":"Augmentation","Choice_3":"Preservation","Question":"In general, the most effective strategy in promoting biological control of landscape pests is","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Introduction"},"Question 302":{"Choice_0":"The least toxic, most narrow-spectrum alternative that will accomplish management goals","Choice_1":"The most toxic, most narrow-spectrum alternative that will accomplish management goals","Choice_2":"The most toxic, broadest-spectrum alternative that will accomplish management goals","Choice_3":"The least toxic, broadest-spectrum alternative that will accomplish management goals","Question":"When choosing a pesticide, PHC practitioners should choose","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"The least toxic, most narrow-spectrum alternative that will accomplish management goals"},"Question 303":{"Choice_0":"Removing breeding and refuge sites for certain pests","Choice_1":"Providing fresh pruning cuts, which block entry of insects","Choice_2":"Reducing the risk of certain fungal wilts","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"In addition to mitigating potential hazards, crown cleaning provides the added benefit of","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Removing breeding and refuge sites for certain pests"},"Question 304":{"Choice_0":"pollution","Choice_1":"allelopathy","Choice_2":"respiration","Choice_3":"osmotic potential","Question":"The chemical inhibition of growth and development of one plant by another plant is known as","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"allelopathy"},"Question 305":{"Choice_0":"dieback","Choice_1":"leaf spots","Choice_2":"stippling","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following symptoms may indicate pollution damage?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 306":{"Choice_0":"hail","Choice_1":"frost cracks","Choice_2":"lightning strikes","Choice_3":"sunscald","Question":"A tree has symptoms of torn and tattered leaves, as well as broken, bruised, and scarred branches. What might be the cause?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"hail"},"Question 307":{"Choice_0":"trees that are root pruned","Choice_1":"trees that are sold bare root","Choice_2":"trees planted too deeply","Choice_3":"trees planted too shallowly","Question":"Which of the following situations is prone to girdling roots?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"trees planted too shallowly"},"Question 308":{"Choice_0":"Ashes","Choice_1":"Dogwoods","Choice_2":"Walnuts","Choice_3":"Birches","Question":"Which of the following trees is well known for its allelopathic effects on the growth and development of plants growing around it?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"Walnuts"},"Question 309":{"Choice_0":"adventitious root","Choice_1":"tap root","Choice_2":"girdling root","Choice_3":"fibrous root","Question":"A root that grows around or across the stem is called a(n)","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"adventitious root"},"Question 310":{"Choice_0":"transplanted","Choice_1":"hardened off","Choice_2":"defoliated","Choice_3":"compartmentalized","Question":"A plant is more likely to experience freezing and chilling injury if it has not had the chance to become","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"hardened off"},"Question 311":{"Choice_0":"lightning strike","Choice_1":"low temperature","Choice_2":"salt","Choice_3":"high temperature","Question":"Which of the following increases the osmotic potential of soil, drawing water out of roots and creating drought symptoms?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"salt"},"Question 312":{"Choice_0":"wilt","Choice_1":"witch\u2019s broom","Choice_2":"lightning damage","Choice_3":"scorch","Question":"Which of the following is a physical injury?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"lightning damage"},"Question 313":{"Choice_0":"warm, calm days","Choice_1":"cool, calm days","Choice_2":"cool, windy days","Choice_3":"warm, windy days","Question":"What are ideal days to avoid accidental drift while spraying herbicides?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"cool, calm days"},"Question 314":{"Choice_0":"sufficient oxygen","Choice_1":"sufficient pore space","Choice_2":"sufficient water","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Compacted soil often lacks which factor necessary for plant survival?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 315":{"Choice_0":"leaf scorch","Choice_1":"sunburn","Choice_2":"wilting","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following is a symptom caused by stress related to high temperature?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 316":{"Choice_0":"sunscald","Choice_1":"hardening off","Choice_2":"frost cracks","Choice_3":"ice damage","Question":"What type of injury is caused by the rapid change in temperature that results from solar heating?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"sunscald"},"Question 317":{"Choice_0":"acute","Choice_1":"anatomic","Choice_2":"biotic","Choice_3":"chronic","Question":"A tree that has been exposed to high concentration of toxic compounds over a relatively short period of time is suffering from what type of toxicity?","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"acute"},"Question 318":{"Choice_0":"respiration","Choice_1":"abscission","Choice_2":"defoliation","Choice_3":"compartmentalization","Question":"A tree\u2019s natural process of defense by which chemical and physical boundaries are created to limit the spread of disease and decay organisms is known as","Topic":"Diagnosis and Treatment","Answer":"compartmentalization"},"Question 319":{"Choice_0":"carbon storage","Choice_1":"carbon uptake","Choice_2":"carbon sequestration","Choice_3":"carbon release","Question":"As tees grow, they take up carbon from carbon dioxide and store it in the form of wood, this is called","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"carbon sequestration"},"Question 320":{"Choice_0":"reduce stress of mental fatigue","Choice_1":"improve air quality","Choice_2":"reduce stormwater runoff","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following is the benefit of trees","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 321":{"Choice_0":"establish penalties for noncompliance","Choice_1":"identify what information to be recorded in tree inventory","Choice_2":"provide guidelines and requirements for obtaining permits for tree removal","Choice_3":"specify responsibility for enforcement","Question":"A typical tree ordinance will not","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"identify what information to be recorded in tree inventory"},"Question 322":{"Choice_0":"standard","Choice_1":"specification","Choice_2":"ordinance","Choice_3":"order","Question":"A __________ is an established or widely recognized authority of acceptable performance.","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"standard"},"Question 323":{"Choice_0":"Council of Landscape Auditors","Choice_1":"Society of Consulting Arborists","Choice_2":"society of commercial Arborists","Choice_3":"Council of Tree and Landscape Appraisers","Question":"A commonly used set of methods for appraising trees was developed by the","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"Council of Tree and Landscape Appraisers"},"Question 324":{"Choice_0":"green infrastructure","Choice_1":"grey infrastructure","Choice_2":"blue infrastructure","Choice_3":"yellow infrastructure","Question":"The trees in cities are part of a","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"green infrastructure"},"Question 325":{"Choice_0":"tree size","Choice_1":"fertilization quantities","Choice_2":"tree value","Choice_3":"watering requirements","Question":"The CTLA trunk formula method calculate","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"tree value"},"Question 326":{"Choice_0":"planting single species in the same district","Choice_1":"planting 20 percent of single species","Choice_2":"planting tree species that are tolerant to hardy in the climate","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following statement about tree planting is correct?","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"planting tree species that are tolerant to hardy in the climate"},"Question 327":{"Choice_0":"protect unapproved trees removal","Choice_1":"preserve tree during land developments","Choice_2":"protect single or multiple trees","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Tree preservation orders are established to","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"all of the above"},"Question 328":{"Choice_0":"Evergreen trees should be planted on the south and west sides of buildings","Choice_1":"Deciduous trees should be planted on the south and west sides of buildings","Choice_2":"Deciduous tree should be planted on the north and east sides of buildings","Choice_3":"all of the above","Question":"Which of the following statement about tree planting location is advisable?","Topic":"Urban Forestry","Answer":"Deciduous trees should be planted on the south and west sides of buildings"},"Question 329":{"Choice_0":"Bark tracing","Choice_1":"Stripping","Choice_2":"Inscribing","Choice_3":"Girdling","Question":"If bark is damaged and loosened during construction, the practice of removing the loose bark and carefully cutting off any jagged edges with a sharp knife is called","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Bark tracing"},"Question 330":{"Choice_0":"Design","Choice_1":"Grading","Choice_2":"Planning","Choice_3":"Maintenance","Question":"The phase of development that involves the creation of plans and supporting documents to describe the project is called.","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Planning"},"Question 331":{"Choice_0":"Attempt to preserve all existing trees on site and persuade the developer to build around them","Choice_1":"Plan to save only the trees that the developer thinks are attractive","Choice_2":"Remove all but a few key trees and work with the landscape architect on a plan to plant new trees and shrubs","Choice_3":"Work with the developer and evaluate each tree\u2019s condition and suitability for preservation","Question":"In planning for the preservation of trees on a construction site, the arborist should","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Work with the developer and evaluate each tree\u2019s condition and suitability for preservation"},"Question 332":{"Choice_0":"Cover the root zone with a 6- to 12- inch (15- to 30-cm) layer of mulch","Choice_1":"Place large plywood sheets over mulch to distribute the weight of heavy vehicles","Choice_2":"Limit the movement of machinery and vehicles on and off the site to one access route","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"An effective means of protecting a root system form compaction during construction would be to","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 333":{"Choice_0":"Beneath the original grade","Choice_1":"On top of a layer of gravel or stone","Choice_2":"In direct contact with the original grade","Choice_3":"In direct contact with tree island walls","Question":"For best penetration of water and oxygen when fill soil is used, the fill soil should be placed","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"In direct contact with the original grade"},"Question 334":{"Choice_0":"Distribute organic mulch over the root zone","Choice_1":"Prohibit heavy equipment form the construction site","Choice_2":"Keep any disturbance outside the tree protection zone","Choice_3":"Monitor soil moisture in the root zone","Question":"When fill soil is installed, the most effective treatment for reducing root damage is to","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Keep any disturbance outside the tree protection zone"},"Question 335":{"Choice_0":"Suffocate the root system","Choice_1":"Improve the soil quality in the root zone","Choice_2":"Improve water absorption in the fine roots","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Adding a few inches of soil over a tree\u2019s root zone may","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Suffocate the root system"},"Question 336":{"Choice_0":"Public agency\u2019s project approval","Choice_1":"Commitment of the project superintendent","Choice_2":"Permitted number of changes to plans in the field","Choice_3":"None of the above","Question":"One of the most critical commitments to the ensured success of a tree preservation project is the","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"None of the above"},"Question 337":{"Choice_0":"Maintenance","Choice_1":"Construction","Choice_2":"Grading","Choice_3":"Planning","Question":"The phase of development that involves selecting the most feasible and appropriate use of the land is called","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Planning"},"Question 338":{"Choice_0":"Location of trees in relation to buildings and infrastructure","Choice_1":"Protection zone","Choice_2":"Specific mitigation and preservation measures","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"A well-drawn plan for detailing a project\u2019s tree preservation strategy should include","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 339":{"Choice_0":"10 percent","Choice_1":"30 percent","Choice_2":"50 percent","Choice_3":"70 percent","Question":"The ideal soil for root growth and development should include pore space equal to about","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"50 percent"},"Question 340":{"Choice_0":"Tree species and its adaptability","Choice_1":"Amount of the root system that is severed or affected","Choice_2":"Amount of paving that will occur near the root zone","Choice_3":"Soil conditions around the tree","Question":"The most important factor in a tree\u2019s survival after grade changes occur is the","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Amount of the root system that is severed or affected"},"Question 341":{"Choice_0":"Reduce the spread of decay to internal tree components","Choice_1":"Accelerate a tree\u2019s production of woundwood after damage has occurred","Choice_2":"Are required by the client","Choice_3":"Are neither required nor recommended","Question":"In most cases, wound dressings","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Are neither required nor recommended"},"Question 342":{"Choice_0":"Supervise all construction work","Choice_1":"Communicate with the project superintendent","Choice_2":"Monitor injury to trees and provide correcting action","Choice_3":"Maintain the TPZ","Question":"Which of the following is not one of the five tasks arborists commonly undertake during the construction phase?","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Supervise all construction work"},"Question 343":{"Choice_0":"Root tracing","Choice_1":"Radial trenching","Choice_2":"Vertical mulching","Choice_3":"Mulch irrigation","Question":"Making holes in the ground over the root zone with a drill or air tool, and then filling them with organic matter, such as compost or peat moss, is called","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Vertical mulching"},"Question 344":{"Choice_0":"Should be limited to crown thinning, but no more than one-third of the overall canopy","Choice_1":"Should include removal of only split, broken, dead, or other potentially hazardous limbs","Choice_2":"Should be continued on a bimonthly schedule for several years","Choice_3":"Is necessary in order to compensate for root loss due to digging or compaction","Question":"Pruning to treat injuries after construction","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Should include removal of only split, broken, dead, or other potentially hazardous limbs"},"Question 345":{"Choice_0":"Each level of development","Choice_1":"The planning and selection phase only","Choice_2":"The presence of heavy machinery on site","Choice_3":"Landscape establishment","Question":"Successful preservation of existing trees on construction sites can be achieved with the commitment of everyone involved during","Topic":"Tree Protection","Answer":"Each level of development"},"Question 346":{"Choice_0":"Observations","Choice_1":"Measurements","Choice_2":"Recommendations","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"A standard assessment form should be used in the risk assessment process to document all","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 347":{"Choice_0":"Noticeable taper","Choice_1":"Codominant stems and included bark","Choice_2":"A lean that has produced reaction wood over the course of its life","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"When performing a risk assessment, an indication of a significant defect is a tree with","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Codominant stems and included bark"},"Question 348":{"Choice_0":"X-ray","Choice_1":"Acoustic tomograph","Choice_2":"Increment borer","Choice_3":"Resistance-recording drill","Question":"A device that measures the time it takes for sound to travel between various points around a cross section of a tree is called a(n)","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Acoustic tomograph"},"Question 349":{"Choice_0":"White rot","Choice_1":"Wet wood","Choice_2":"Brown rot","Choice_3":"Soft rot","Question":"A decay caused by fungi that primarily attacks the celluloses, leaving the wood brittle, is called","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Brown rot"},"Question 350":{"Choice_0":"Resistance-recording drill","Choice_1":"Acoustic tomograph","Choice_2":"Increment borer","Choice_3":"X-ray","Question":"A device used to drill into trunk or root tissue and extract a core for examination is called a(n)","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Increment borer"},"Question 351":{"Choice_0":"Identify characteristics associated with tree failure","Choice_1":"Accurately predict tree failure","Choice_2":"Identify potential hazard without the use of a systematic process","Choice_3":"None of the above","Question":"With training and experience, an arborist can learn to visually assess tree structure to","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Identify characteristics associated with tree failure"},"Question 352":{"Choice_0":"Installing a lightning protection system","Choice_1":"Filling the cavity","Choice_2":"Pruning","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"A common risk mitigation practice is","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Pruning"},"Question 353":{"Choice_0":"Advise clients about the level of risk a tree presents","Choice_1":"Recommend possible methods of risk reduction","Choice_2":"Inform clients on possible damages in case of tree failure","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"After assessing a tree\u2019s failure potential, the arborist\u2019s role is to","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"All of the above"},"Question 354":{"Choice_0":"Epiphytes","Choice_1":"Sapwood rot","Choice_2":"Heart rot","Choice_3":"Reaction","Question":"The presence of numerous, small fruiting bodies of a wood decay organism on a tree bark is usually an","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Sapwood rot"},"Question 355":{"Choice_0":"Trenching","Choice_1":"Grade changes","Choice_2":"Soil compaction","Choice_3":"All of the above","Question":"Tree root loss, whether obvious or hidden, may be the result of","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Grade changes"},"Question 356":{"Choice_0":"Encumbrance","Choice_1":"Hindrance","Choice_2":"Interference","Choice_3":"Negligence","Question":"The legal term for failure to exercise due to care is","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Negligence"},"Question 357":{"Choice_0":"Drainage problems","Choice_1":"Pruning requirements","Choice_2":"Risk","Choice_3":"Diseases","Question":"The goal of tree risk assessment and management is to minimize","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Risk"},"Question 358":{"Choice_0":"Leaf wilt","Choice_1":"Galls","Choice_2":"Carpenter ants","Choice_3":"Sapsuckers","Question":"Which of the following is considered an indicator of tree decay?","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Carpenter ants"},"Question 359":{"Choice_0":"Disease","Choice_1":"Defect","Choice_2":"Pest infestation","Choice_3":"Target","Question":"The determining factor for establishing risk is the presence of a","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Target"},"Question 360":{"Choice_0":"Visual inspections of the leaves, branches, and bark","Choice_1":"A varied course of action based on each specific tree","Choice_2":"Examination of the leaves for biotic disorders","Choice_3":"Assessments of the tree, its history","Question":"The main components of a complete and systematic tree inspection process are","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Visual inspections of the leaves, branches, and bark"},"Question 361":{"Choice_0":"Happenstance","Choice_1":"Causation","Choice_2":"Probability","Choice_3":"Hearsay","Question":"Determination of liability addressed by the courts and is based in part on","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Causation"},"Question 362":{"Choice_0":"Bending strength","Choice_1":"Flexibility","Choice_2":"Cellulose","Choice_3":"Compressive strength","Question":"Lignin is a compound within a tree\u2019s cellular structure that gives wood its","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"Bending strength"},"Question 363":{"Choice_0":"The arborist","Choice_1":"The tree owner\/manager","Choice_2":"A risk rating system","Choice_3":"An acoustic device","Question":"The decision regarding the level of risk that is acceptable must be made by","Topic":"Tree Risk Assessment","Answer":"The tree owner\/manager"}}